Jiayi (Kayee) Zhou

Unit 314, 4600 Elmont Dr., Austin, TX 78741 (806) 939-5062 • <u>kayee@utexas.edu</u>

BIO

Doctoral Student of Public Policy, MA and MPA in Political Science graduate with 7+ years of experience conducting and assisting research projects, involving immigration and immigrant policies, race, ethnicity, and identity politics, and public policies of China. Proficient in data processing, statistical analysis, and machine learning for text analysis by using Stata and R, and qualitative methods, including interviews and focus groups. My dissertation project on U.S. local governments' immigrant integration policies is a three-paper format that addresses the following questions: (1) How do local integration policies affect immigrants' political participation, the primary outcome of political incorporation policies? (2) How do immigrants with different group identities (e.g., members of immigrants, members of racial and ethnic groups, or members of the American society) respond to local integration policies in terms of their political actions? (3) How do local governments cooperate with immigrant-focused nonprofit organizations in terms of helping immigrants incorporate into the U.S.?

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Public Affairs Expected May 2024

University of Texas, Austin, TX

• GPA: 3.93

MA in Political Science

May 2019

Texas Tech University, Lubbock, TX

• GPA: 3.84

MPA in Political Science

May 2017

June 2015

Texas Tech University, Lubbock, TX

• GPA: 3.93

BA in Law

Sun Yat-Sen University, Guangzhou, China
Majors: Political Science and Public Administration

• GPA: 3.6

PUBLICATIONS & PRESENTATIONS

Zhou, Kayee, and Dennis Patterson. "Changing patterns of Asian-American partisanship: Accounting for the politicization of the US's fastest growing minority." Social Science Quarterly 102.4 (2021): 1428-1438.

Ye, Lin, Yingling Gao, and Kayee Zhou. "提高产能空间, 城市升值构动力 [Optimizing City's Production Capacity to Improve its Competitiveness]." In 破局: 中国治理变革的地方样本 [Break the Deadlock: Exploring the Chinese way of local governance reform], edited by Yanling He, 98–129. 社会科学文献出版社 [Social Sciences Academic Press], 2018.

Working Papers

Impacts of U.S. Local Immigrant Integration Policies on Immigrants' Political Participation Immigrants' Group Identities and Collective Actions

Dynamics of Governmental Cooperation with Immigrant-focused Nonprofits

A Power Ascension Model of Policy Making in Authoritarian Systems: Evidence from China.

Coauthored with Dr. Dennis Patterson

The Electoral Cycle and Public Policy: Implications for Research and Theory Integration.

Coauthored with Dr. Dennis Patterson

I Am Who I Vote For: A Hierarchical Network Model of Party Identification

Coauthored with God'swill Osa, Ajay Somaraju, Sarah Heise

Attitudinal and Behavioral Sorting in the United States

Coauthored with Sarah Heise, Ajay Somaraju, God'swill Osa

Presentations

The Electoral Cycle and Public Policy: Implications for Research and Theory Integration.

Coauthored with Dr. Dennis Patterson, Texas Tech University. Presented at the 2022 Annual Meeting of the Midwest Political Science Association, Chicago.

Asian American Group Identity, Consciousness, and Political Participation. Presented at the 2021 American Political Science Association's Annual Meeting & Exhibition, Seattle.

A Power Ascension Model of Policy Making in Authoritarian Systems: Evidence from China.

Coauthored with Dr. Dennis Patterson, Texas Tech University. Presented at the 2020 Annual Meeting of the Midwest Political Science Association, Chicago.

An Electoral Cycle Theory of Public Policy Making. Coauthored with Dr. Dennis Patterson, Texas Tech University. Presented at the 2019 Annual Meeting of the Southern Political Science Association, Austin.

Explaining the Partisan Preferences of Asian Americans. Coauthored with Dr. Dennis Patterson, Texas Tech University. Presented at the 2019 Annual Meeting of the Midwest Political Science Association, Chicago.

Toward Political Theory of Public Policy. Coauthored with Dr. Dennis Patterson, Texas Tech University. Presented at the 2018 Annual Meeting of the Midwest Political Science Association, Chicago.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE & WORKSHOP

Graduate Research Assistant

September 2020 – January 2022

Projects: Texas Home Visiting Program - Describing Home Visiting's Value Evaluation III: The Connection Between THV and Child Wellbeing, at the Child and Family Research Partnership (CFRP) center

Protective and compensatory experience, at the CFRP center

- Cleaned, matched, processed, and analyzed large datasets using Stata and R
- Created analysis report based on produced results

Graduate Research Assistant

March 2020 – June 2020

Project: The Effectiveness of Public Agricultural Extension: Evidence from Farmer Field Days in Kenya, with Dr. Raissa Fabregas

• Matched and merged multiple datasets and performed analysis using Stata, transformed results with LaTeX and verified analytical results, and edited papers.

Member of the Research Team

Spring 2015

Project: Analyze the Separation of Administration and Economic Reform among Village Committees, Nanhai District, China

- Collected and analyzed policy documents, minutes from meetings, and progress reports about the reform from local governments and village committees.
- Interviewed with leaders of village committees and residents' committees on the reform.

Research Assistant September 2014

Project: Evaluate the Administrative Approval Reform of Local Government, Luogang District, China

- Reviewed policy documents, minutes from meetings and implementation plans about the reform conducted by the Luogang government.
- Conducted interviews with heads of various departments in the Luogang government.

Research Assistant Summer 2014

Project: Assess Social Work Agencies' Performance in Providing Elder Care Services, Nanhai District, China

- Conducted documentation reviews and observations to evaluate 5 agencies' performances.
- Interviewed 10 leaders, 13 frontline social workers, and 20 clients on agencies' services.
- Gave advice to the agencies and contributed to the evaluation report.

Research Assistant Summer 2014

Project: Research on the Elder Care Services in Nanhai District, China

- Conducted participant observation at Nursing Home at Danzao Town for 3 months.
- Implemented a survey on 700 elders over 60 years old.
- Had 20 interviews with the staff of nursing homes and social work agencies.
- Contributed to the report with recommendations to the government by comparing China's efforts with social welfare policies of developed countries

Member of the Research Team

Summer 2014

Project: Research on the Local Culture of the Historic Villages, Nanhai District, China

- Collected, reviewed and evaluated family documents and historical records of an ancient village in Danzao Town, such as records on the lives and kinship ties of ancestors and stories of historical architecture.
- Conducted oral history interviews with 3 villagers.
- Wrote a report on the history of the village, including stories of the village's founders, names and historical buildings.
- Presented the results at the local culture research competition and made an exhibition at Danzao Town to introduce the hidden local culture to the public.

Member of the Research Team

Fall 2013

Project: Research on the School Consolidation in China

- Reviewed policy documents and news on the school consolidation.
- Wrote a report based on a case study on the school consolidation happened in a poverty county.
- Presented the report at the Sun Yat-sen University Public Administration Case Competition and won the 2nd prize out of 140 teams.

TEACHING SERVICE

Teaching Assistant

September 2022 – Present

Lyndon B. Johnson School of Public Affairs, University of Texas at Austin

- Holding two sections per week for over 30 master students in the class of analytical methods for global policy studies.
- Tutored both quantitative and qualitative methods and the use of Stata in data analysis.

Teaching Assistant

September 2015 – May 2019

Department of Political Science, Texas Tech University

- Tutored over 300 students in classes of American Government and Texas Politics per semester.
- Graded written responses and responded to students' questions.

OTHER EMPLOYMENT

Administrative Intern

June 2016 - December 2016

Ransom Canyon Administration Department, Lubbock, TX

- Prepared orientation materials for newly elected council members.
- Wrote job descriptions for the officials of the government of Ransom Canyon, including the mayor, city manager, and department heads
- Wrote memos to the city council members after collecting and analyzing data from Texas Municipal Retirement System, suggesting lowering the Employee Deposit Rate to 3% or 5% and increasing the Municipal Current Matching Ratio to 2:1.

Administrative Intern

April 2015 - July 2015

Department of Social Work, Nanhai Civil Affairs Bureau, China

- Managed the department's general administrative activities, including arranging meetings and training, managing office supplies, and answering queries by social work agencies or social workers.
- Prepared annual department budget planning of \$120,000.
- Helped initiate a policy on supporting social workers in Nanhai District, which was enacted, including subsidies for licensed social workers (on average \$200 per person), social work interns (\$85 per person per month), and startup local social work agencies (\$4,500 per organization per year).

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

President-Elect

July 2018 – May 2019

High Plains Chapter, American Society for Public Administration

Vice President

Fall 2016 – Spring 2017

Public Administration Graduate Association, Texas Tech Political Science Department

Helped new students of the MPA program with information on classes and resources of Texas
 Tech Political Science Department.

AWARDS

LBJ School Fellowship	Fall 2019 – Present
Lyndon B. Johnson School of Public Affairs, University of Texas at Austin	
Cochran Public Administration AS Scholarship	Fall 2017
Department of Political Science, Texas Tech University	
Norwood Graduate Public Administration Scholarship	Fall 2015 – Spring 2017
Department of Political Science, Texas Tech University	
Barron Public Administration Scholarship	Fall 2015 – Spring 2017
Department of Political Science, Texas Tech University	
The First Class Scholarship	Fall 2013 – Spring 2014
School of Government, Sun Yat-Sen University	
Times China Holdings Limited Scholarship	Fall 2013 – Spring 2014
School of Government, Sun Yat-Sen University	

PROFESSIONAL STRENGTHS

Language

English, Mandarin & Cantonese

- Proficient speaking, listening and writing skills in English.
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills in Mandarin and Cantonese.

Research Skills:

- Proficient in defining a specific research problem and conducting solid literature review
- Proficient in applying the appropriate methodological approach in the collection and analysis of data.
- Familiar with conveying anticipated findings that lend a practical prescriptive resolution to the issues and problems being assessed
- Familiar with composing/communicating the research in a manner easily understood by both technical and non-technical audiences.
- Proficient in planning research schedules and scheduling personal timelines to ensure the progress of the research.

Data Analysis Software

Stata & R

- Proficient in data processing and linear regression analysis using Stata and R, including testing violations and running diagnostics of the linear model.
- Proficient in data processing and statistical analysis and diagnostics for categorical and discrete variables using Stata and R, such as logit and probit models, multinomial logit models, hierarchical/multilevel models, and latent class models.
- Proficient in text analysis using R, including scraping, data cleaning and pre-processing, and training various machine learning models to predict results.